christian@bingham.is www.bingham.is 814.440.5467

about

A career spent launching SaaS tech for the world's largest brands & media platforms. Goldman Sachs alum. Founded & sold Waypoint Media. 70th hire @ AppNexus (now Xandr). Expert at building successful consulting teams.

technical skills

Advertising Tech (DSP, SSP, DMP, CDP, RTB), Cloud (SaaS, PaaS, IaaS), REST API, scripting, SQL, Unix/Linux, Python, privacy & identity, data migrations, data warehousing, data lakes

experience

Oracle

Principal Architect, Data Cloud

2018—Present

Data Cloud is an identity platform that helps connect, control, and activate customer data

- Managing delivery of high-value partner architectures. My programs range from new platform designs to infrastructure modernization & maintenance
- Technical advisor to partner leadership on advertising-focused data solutions: Privacy, behavioral targeting & identity resolution, data lakes, data warehousing, etc.
- Creator of open-source tools designed to streamline interactions with RESTful APIs
- Published white paper discussing privacy-by-design business strategies & tech: link.bingham.is/privacy

Upwardly Group

Director of Product and Implementation

2017-2018

Upwardly Group is an Ad Tech consulting collective

- Directed Programmatic business strategy, oversaw Trading & Finance teams
- Managed strategic partnerships, guided new platform relationships through all phases of the execution lifecycle (pitch, scoping, contract, implementation)
- Developed financial modeling to forecast +\$8MM of client budget & company revenue;
 achieved 1.1% of target prediction

Waypoint Media

Co-Founder, VP of Client Services

Acquired by FanAl 2013 – 2017

Waypoint was an advertising platform built to monetizing livestreaming video. We invented the unblockable video ad format

- Acquired by Fan.ai. TechCrunch press release: <u>link.bingham.is/exit</u>
- At peak, our tech reached 45M viewers each month. Used by tier-1 streaming companies like Amazon & Twitch.tv to power live advertising needs
- Steered the company toward profitability, managed client go-to-market strategies
- Principal Design Product Manager: Led design & development of UI/UX, client media, Sales collateral

AppNexus

Acquired by AT&T 2010 – 2013

Senior Implementation Consultant, Global Accounts

AppNexus was the world's largest independent digital advertising platform

- 70th employee. Led Publisher Integrations team: 12 direct reports
- Managed large-scale, technical enterprise relationships

AppNexus London

 Product Manager for company's first server-to-server APIs, first video exchange product, developed private exchange best-practices, etc.

Relocated to London to scale the company's first international Global Services team

- Drove 2x headcount growth
- Led hiring, training, continuity across international offices

Goldman Sachs

Financial Analyst, Global Control

2008 - 2010

Regulatory oversight for Asian & domestic security activity, weekly value ~\$2.5BN USD

 Founding member of an open source, internal Knowledgebase accessible to over 25,000 employees worldwide

hobbies

I love to tinker with hardware and hack around software. Past projects:

Open-Source Firewalls – Custom-built, solid-state appliances designed to protect networks against foreign traffic, malware, & suspicious activity

Bootloader Hacking – Installing OSes on unsupported hardware

education

Lehigh University

B.S., Mechanical Engineering